kirupatext=Dear clients,
If you are considering the possibility of a business visit to Florida for the purpose of expanding your commercial activities in the form of reality investments, we present your our services:

BUSINESS TRIP TO USA - Florida for one week.
Rental of room with facilities (bathroom, dressing room, swiming pool), local reality offices meetings organization, accompanying in searching for selected properties, assistance in formality executions.
Assistance in individual negotiations according to the demands of our clients.
Price: USD 750,-
