kirupatext=The Green Card Lottery
The US Department of Foreign Affairs organizes the Green Card Lottery every year – a unique opportunity to gain an official permission to reside and work in the USA.
The applicant must be of 18 years of age or older, must have completed his secondary education – alternatively a two-year course in his area of work within the last five years. The rules for applying are very strict, and every single error, however marginal, will result in the application being rejected. For that reason, we would highly recommend using the services of our office to avoid possible filing errors. If you decide to take advantage of the services of our office, the application has to be filed before the 5th of December. Our fee is $80,- for each person, or $60,- for every additional person form one family.
All required information can be filed with our office in electronic form via e-mail, or using our Prague postal address. To file your application, following information would be required: First name, eventually Christian name and surname, eventually original surname. Date and place of birth, nationality and country of citizenship, contact address including telephone number. Residence address (if it differs form contact address). The same information is required for your wife/husband and any unmarried child under 21 years of age. Also you would have to provide us with  photograph of yourself (and all that apply within your family application). The photograph has to be in the following format: electronic (320x320 px, 150 dpi, 24 bit, JPEG up to the size of 62,500 bytes) postal (50x50mm). The face has to be on a light background, covering at least 50 per-cent of the photograph, with no glasses or hats.
.

