kirupatext=AAAAAAAAAAAAAAWe present you our offer of establishing offshore companies in USA, state Florida, together with some basic introductory information. Establishing an offshore company in Florida is not only advantageous from the perspective of your commercial operations, but mainly from the tax planning perspective. Entire agenda of establishing and operation of the company can be handled without even the need of traveling to Florida through our local agents. We shall establish your bank account at the SunTrust bank – with internet access, check book and a VISA card. You shall be the only one having the access to the bank account through selected passwords. In the Florida company register, the owner of the company is not listed, only the companies’ listed agent and manager. These services, together with providing a mailing address for your company and a re-mailing service, are provided all by us, through our Florida legal office. Credibility and discreetness of this relationship and services is ensured by the legal standards of state Florida and a sanction of license abolishment. Apart from administrative fees, that are already embedded in our fee, the company does not pay any income tax. When collecting the companies profit, each partner in the company shall pay an individual personal tax of about 12 per cent of his entire income up to $ 30 000 / year.The state of Florida does not require any minimum capital of the company. The process of establishing only requires a photocopy of passports and driving licenses of the future stockholders. The total number of stockholders cannot exceed 70, so that the company would not lose the benefits of a small company. We will gladly provide you with more information in our Prague office, on the following address:

800 Indus Rd., 34293 Venice, Florida - tel./fax 1 941 408 8622
El.Přemyslovny 425, Praha 5 - Zbraslav  -  tel.: 602 82 82 43  -  e-mail:info@uscorpllc.com
